特别行动组训练站
阿拉斯加
谍影重重4：伯恩的遗产
伦敦有个叫赛门·罗斯的记者
KRAMER: There's a reporter in London named Simon Ross.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
我们发现了一些不利于我们的通话记录 里面提到了他
We caught some phone chatter we didn't like and his name came up.
他们派出去人打探一下
They put a team out there to take a better look.
整天都监视着他
They've been sitting on him pretty fight all day.
马里兰州 贝塞斯达
我一个小时之前接到一个电话 我们遇到麻烦了
I just got a can about an hour ago. We got a real problem here.
什么问题
TURSO: What kind of problem?
这个人是给卫报撰稿的
This guy's a writer for The Guardian.
他准备爆料杰森·伯恩踩石计划以及黑石楠计划
He's preparing an expose on Jason Bourne, Treadstone and Blackbriar.
消息来源是
Sourced how?
不知道
Unknown.
伯恩泄的密吗 可能吗
From Bourne? Is it possible?
可能吗
Possible?
我们六周前发现伯恩在莫斯科
We had Bourne six weeks ago in Moscow.
他受了伤 没有交通工具 一队哥萨克人在追捕他
He was on foot, wounded, with a full Cossack posse up his ass.
他也不知用了什么方法 竟逃了出来
Somehow, he walked out of there.
我都不知道还有什么不可能的
I've kind of lost my perspective on what's possible.
你好像很累 埃兹拉
You sound tired, Ezra.
如果我是你 我会更努力
I would make more of an effort if I were you.
你是美国中情局的主管
You're the director of the Central Intelligence Agency
拜托 像个主管的样子
of the United States of America, for God's sake. Act like it.
如果这事儿出点查错连累到我 马克…
If I go down for this, Mark, if this goes any more wrong...
埃兹拉
Ezra,
我们给你们辆法拉利 你们却像割草机一样对待
you were given a Ferrari and your people treated it like a lawn mower.
弄坏了 后果就得自己承担 就是这样
You break it, you bought it. It was ever thus.
也许我应该直接找瑞克·拜亚
Well, maybe I should be speaking directly to Ric Byer.
不 不用了 你的麻烦已经够多了
No,no,no. You're in enough trouble already.
我来通知他吧
I'll let him know.
(WOLVES BARKING)
(WOLVES WHIMPERING)
(YELLS)
弗吉尼亚州 雷斯顿
(WIND HOWLING)
华盛顿
国家研究分析小组
朱莉 就这些了吧 太好了 谢谢
DITA: Julie, is that the last of them? Terrific, thank you.
对 踩石计划的最后一次审计吗
BYER: So, the last audit on Treadstone?
第三页
INGRAM: Third page.
七周前
DITA: Seven weeks ago.
这是中情局的资料 还是我们的
This is from the CIA, or this is ours?
不是 是他们的
Oh, no. It's theirs.
这一堆都是他们的
This whole pile is theirs.
有人看过这些资料吗
Is anybody reading these ground cables?
我们要找多少资料
INGRAM: Look, how wide are we digging?
什么叫多少能找的都得找
What do you mean, "how wide?" Just get me everything.
踩石 黑石楠 结果 拉克斯所有病毒项目都得查
Treadstone, Blackbriar, Outcome, LARX. All the beta programs.
也就是说从翡翠湖开始
And that means take it all the way back to Emerald Lake.
我需要所有起转折作用的事件 所有研发人员的资料
I want all points of convergence, I want all research personnel,
我要知道什么人在什么时间
I want to know about anybody who talked
跟谁都谈了些什么
to anybody about anything at any time.
说真的 有人看过伯恩的资料吗
Seriously, has anybody looked at this stuff on Bourne?
这些现场报告太不可思议了
The field reports. It's incredible.
三年没参加任何项目 没医疗记录 是第一代实验体 但还活着
Three years off-program, non-med, first-gen, still rolling.
如果我们能弄到这些数据…
If there's any way we can score some data off of this...
如果他们能活捉他…
If they caught him alive...
这也能算参考值了吧
I mean, even as a baseline.
哪怕找到的尸体也好
Even forensically.
你是不是开错会了
Maybe you're in the wrong meeting.
因为我们的会是要讨论情报泄露的
Because the meeting that we're having is about an infection.
我们要讨论的这次泄露非常严重
We're here talking about a serious infection
我们要尽快确定情报传播面有多广
and all we're trying to do is determine how far it's spread
这样才能知道舍弃多少东西才能自救
so that we know how much we have to cut to save the patient.
你从没听说过踩石计划
You have never heard of Treadstone.
还有伯恩… 我才不在乎他们是让他曝尸街头还是拿尸袋装他呢
And Bourne... I don't care if they bag him and drop the body on the sidewalk.
我们不管那个
We're not going to touch it.
你现在不要想别的了
You're going to turn off that side of your head now
跟上我们的思路
and get with the rest of us here.
现在你该想想如果情况失控
And you're going to start to consider the magnitude of what we're facing
我们要做哪些工作
if this moves sideways on us.
因为如果我们开始调查 四处打探
Because if we get into this, we dig around,
最后发现这些中情局的小丑
and we find out these CIA clowns
让踩石这个烂摊子危及到我们其它项目了 该怎么办
have let this Treadstone mess metastasize into the rest of these programs?
祈祷不会发生这种事吧
Just pray that that doesn't happen.
(GUN FIRES)
伦敦 滑铁卢车站
(MAN ANNOUNCING ON PA)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
我们刚从滑铁卢站得到消息
MALE ANCHOR: We're just getting reports coming in now from Waterloo Station
那里发生了枪击事件
that there has been a shooting.
接下来我们连线杰瑞米·汤普森为您现场报道
Let's take you live down there and speak to Jeremy Thompson.
杰瑞米
Jeremy?
滑铁卢站依然很混乱
There's still an awful lot of confusion here at Waterloo Station.
大家可以看到 救护车已经来了
As you can see, ambulances have been called up.
受害者赛门·罗斯是一名
The victim, Simon Ross, was a veteran reporter
伦敦卫报的资深记者
with The Guardian newspaper in London.
当场被宣布死亡
He was pronounced dead at the scene.
警方称至少开了一枪
Police are now telling us there was at least one,
最多可能开了三枪
and possibly as many as three, shots fired.
伦敦卫报记者赛门·罗斯…
Simon Ross, a reporter with The Guardian newspaper...
-嘿 詹姆斯 -嘿
-Hey, James. -Hey.
该死 对不起 我不知道我还回来
Oh, shit, sorry. I didn't know I was coming back.
没关系
It's all right.
(ELECTRONIC BEEP)
告诉希尔科特医生我来了 好吗
Can you tell Dr. Hillcott I'm here?
好的
You got it.
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
明天见
See you tomorrow.
(BEEPS)
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
不知道他会来
I had no idea he was coming in.
-是六号 -六号
-It's Number Six. -Number Six?
七月以来就没见过他
We haven't seen him since July.
嗯嗯 好的
Mmm-hmm. Okay.
我需要新的基板 胆碱 神经传导药物
"Need new base panels, choline profile, nerve conduction."
我需要对他做全套检测
I want a full engraftment workup.
我要给抗原部打电话 看能不能得到同意让他多待一会儿
I'm gonna call NRAG and see if we can't get approval to put him under.
趁他还活着的时候 我得弄个骨髓样本
I want a marrow and a full spinal while we have him.
好的
Okay.
(TYPING ON KEYBOARD)
(DOOR BUZZES)
他怎么样
How is he?
准备好了
He's prepped.
他等的时候 喝了半升水
He drank a half-liter of water while he was waiting.
他去年肾脏出了问题
He had some renal issues last year.
也许他只是渴了呢
Or maybe he was thirsty.
我有个待定任务
I have a pending task request.
我知道 我看过了
I know, I read it.
我准备完成皮质研究
I'm trying to complete my cortex study.
他的静脉中会有更持续的对比
He'll get a more sustained contrast off an IV.
我被通过了
I'm approved?
是的
Mmm-hmm.
太好了 谢谢
Yes! Thank you!
抱歉让你久等了
Sorry to keep you waiting.
好久不见了
We haven't seen you in a while
所以我们得做全套检查
so we're going to be doing a full spec workup.
我三个月前刚做了全套检查
I just had a full spec three months ago.
没错 我们更改了检查周期
Yeah, well, we had to change the boundary schedules
你正好比新标准晚来了一个星期
and you're a week over the newline.
这么说吧 如果我早来十天
Let me get this straight, if I had come in
就不用再做一次了
10 days ago, I would have been in the clear?
就不能通融一下 对吧
It never gets any longer, does it?
你得把项链拿下来
You're gonna have to take that off.
今天 很荣幸向你们介绍这个人
-(GLASS TINKLING) -Today, I have the honor of introducing the man
他将为我们介绍今天的贵宾
who is going to introduce our guest of honor.
伯特 有请阿尔伯特·赫什医生
Bert? Doctor Albert Hirsch.
(ALL CLAPPING)
我初遇丹·希尔科特是在1987年
DR. HIRSCH: [first met Dan Hillcott in 1987
那一定是在最无聊的
at what must have been the most boring
神经心理学会议上
neuropsych conference ever held.
我们设法逃离了那个沉闷的宴会厅
We managed to escape that dreary ballroom
去了一个黑暗的角落 喝饮料
and find a dark corner and a cold beverage.
从此以后 我们就一直躲在黑暗的角落
And we've been finding dark corners ever since.
(PEOPLE MURMURING APPROVINGLY)
天呐
TURSO: (SIGHS) My God.
(CHUCKLES)
你从哪找到这录像的
Where did you find this?
优土豆视频网站
YouTube.
我以为所有情报都设了防火墙呢
I thought we had everything firewalled.
我本来也是这么想的
BYER: Yeah, so did I.
我也以为中情局会处理踩石计划
But then again, I thought the CIA would handle Treadstone,
也许我是后知后觉
so maybe I'm just behind the curve.
嗯
Hmm. (SCOFFS)
就这段 没其它的了吧
Well, is that it? Is that all of it?
不 不 显然他们觉得
No, no. They apparently thought it was okay
一起出席这样的场合几次没关系
to attend about a half a dozen of these things together.
这能证明什么
Proving what?
我们看到踩石和结果的医学顾问
We're looking at the medical directors of Treadstone and Outcome
公开庆祝他们的秘密聚会
publicly celebrating their top secret man-crush.
如果伯恩揭露踩石计划 赫什就会被彻底查出来
If this Bourne mess exposes Treadstone, they will turn Hirsch inside out.
可能在我们还不知情的时候 他们就跟希尔科特谈过了
They'll be talking to Hillcott before we even know what happened.
后果会怎样
What's the damage?
整个结果行动计划就毁了
Outcome. We'd lose Outcome.
什么意思
Uh, meaning what?
我们要结束这个项目
Meaning we will burn the program to the ground.
意味着要彻底清理
And I mean from top to bottom.
就因为这录像
Because of this?
就因为他俩是朋友吗
Because they're friends?
这两个人帮我们建立了整个计划平台
These two guys built our platform!
那你希望醒来看见有线电视新闻上播这个吗
You want to wake up and see this on CNN?
天呐 瑞克 就因为这个
Jesus, Ric. Just like that?
赫什和希尔科特
Hirsch and Hillcott?
有多少人能理解这个工作
How many people even understand this work,
更别说从事这工作了
let alone have the will to pursue it?
任何事还都没发生
Nothing has even happened yet!
但我们必须准备好
And we have to get ready.
准备好做什么
Ready for what?
准备好不失去一切 我们保留核心技术 保存好数据
We don't lose it all, we've got the science. We'll keep the data.
我们所有杰索克计划的人应该也很安全
All of our JSOK liaisons seem to be safe.
我们先中止病毒项目
We've got the beta programs tucked away.
停一段时间 避过风头再重建
We'll take a pause, and we'll rebuild it.
我也希望有更好的办法 但是…
I wish there was a better alternative, but...
天呐
God.
(COCKS GUN)
(FIRING)
你要假装不知道我在这吗
Are you going to pretend you don't know I'm here?
我只是出于礼貌
I was just trying to be polite.
我没想到你这么快就到了
I wasn't expecting you so soon.
你干了什么 是翻山越岭过来的吗
What did you do? Did you come over the mountain?
他们没监控我的位置吗
Don't they forward my position?
你比纪录早了两天到达
You beat the record by two days.
-哦 是吗 -是的
-Oh, yeah? -Yeah.
你不知道有纪录吗
You didn't know there was a record?
不知道 没人提过
No. It never came up.
不会是你的纪录吗
It wasn't your record, was it?
没人会翻山过来
No one comes over the mountain.
但我就这么过来的
Yeah, well, I did.
对了 我叫艾伦
I'm Aaron, by the way.
你干嘛这么做
Why did you do that?
如果你没任务 为什么冒险
If you weren't on the clock, Why take the risk?
为什么要选择爬山
Why take the mountain?
我把药弄丢了
I lost my chems.
就因为我把整个药包都弄丢了
I dropped my program kit, that's Why.
好吧
All right.
上头规定我得上报你的到达
Protocol is for me to call in your arrival.
他们肯定会要求你提交血样 你按时抽血了吧
They're going to want a sample pick-up. You got blood work, right?
就今天的没抽
I owe today.
好吧 现在就去抽
All right, pull it now.
无人机三个小时后到
The drone takes about three hours to get up here
所以我先做点饭 你把衣服烘烘干
so I'll get some food started. You can dry your shit.
听着…
So, look...
我真有麻烦了
I got a real problem, here.
我翻山过来 是因为我弄丢了药
I came over that mountain because I lost my chems.
你吃的什么药
What are you taking?
每天的量吗 250毫克绿色的体能药
My daily? Phys meds, 250 green.
400毫克蓝色的改善大脑认知的药
Cognitive programs, 400 blue.
说说怎么弄丢的
Define "lost."
从20米高的山崖掉了下去
Lost. Fell into the rocks off a 20-meter cliff.
这样弄丢的
Lost.
那怎么可能
How is that possible?
听着 自从我离开降落点后
Look, I've had a pack of wolves
一群狼就一直追着我 懂吗
on my ass since I left the drop, okay?
我以为我甩掉它们了 却在河边又被追上了
I thought I lost them, but they came at me at the river,
所以我躲在峡谷里 希望晚上能休息一下
so I took the ledge up to the ravine to try to rally out the night.
但我错了
I chose wrong.
我在野外被发现 没法攀爬
I got caught out in the open, I couldn't climb.
生不了火 手被冻僵了
I couldn't make a fire, my hands got stiff.
所以才弄丢了药
I dropped them.
你真应该把这写下来
You're going to have to write that up.
(CHUCKLES)
那是你的吗
So, is that yours?
什么
Hmm?
那些血样是你的吗
The blood work?
是你的 对吧
That's yours, isn't it?
你根本不是联络员 对吧
You're not a contact, are you?
听我说 我很抱歉就这么揭穿你了
Look, I'm sorry to call you out like that.
只是…
It's just that...
我从没见过项目里的其他人
I have never met anybody in the program before.
从没有 你是…
Never, nobody. You're the...
我知道你这儿有多余的药
I know you have some extra chems here.
在明天你离开之前 我是不能给你的
I'm not supposed to ration you out until you leave tomorrow.
好吧
Yeah.
你今天吃药了吗
Did you chem today?
只吃了绿色的
AARON: Green only.
我已经32小时没吃蓝色的了
I haven't had a blue in 32 hours.
中情局潜伏机构
反恐局 纽约市
大家听着
People, listen up.
我们遇到安全隐患 情况紧急
We have an imminent threat.
这是国家安全紧急事件 优先第五级
This is a national security emergency, priority level five.
是威尔斯的电话
It's Wills.
我是瑞克·拜亚
Ric Byer.
嘿 他回来了
Hey. Uh, he's here.
伯恩回来了 就在纽约
Bourne is here, in New York.
什么
What?
杰森·伯恩现在就在曼哈顿
Jason Bourne is in Manhattan.
已经确认了
Confirmed.
他还活着 我只知道这些 我得挂了
He's alive and mobile. That's all I have. I gotta go.
(MOTOR WHIRRING)
(WOLVES HOWLING)
你的朋友们来了
Your friends are here.
我知道
I know.
你不觉得很奇怪吗
Don't you think that's strange?
那些狼 它们不那样做的
The wolves? They don't do that.
它们不追踪人类
They don't track people.
没错
Yeah.
也许它们不把你当人看
Maybe they don't think you're human.
我们一共有多少人
So, how many of us are there?
你的问题太多了
You ask too many questions.
也许你也不知道
Maybe you don't know, either.
你到底在这干什么
So, what are you doing up here anyway?
你怎么知道我不是来评估你的
How do you know that I'm not evaluating you?
我不知道 你是吗
I don't know. Are you?
也许我不在乎
Maybe I don't care.
你有没有不在乎过什么
Do you ever not care?
也许你在评估我
Maybe you're evaluating me.
我躲开监视四天了 所以来了这儿
I went off the grid for four days, that's why I'm here.
我没去报到检查
I skipped my check-in.
结果现在我还得执行寻物任务
Now I'm on this bullshit scavenger hunt.
他们自有理由
They have their reasons.
是…
Yeah, well...
我以为只是个警告 现在却不那么肯定了
I thought I was having my wrist slapped, but now I'm not so sure.
我还在分辨你是要杀了我
I'm still trying to figure out if you're
还是在给我打气
supposed to kill me or give me a pep talk.
说真的 哥们 你想太多了
Seriously, man, you think too much.
我们不应该是一条绳上的蚂蚱吗
Aren't we wired to stick our nose in, you and I?
我们周围方圆300里都没人
There's not another person for 300 miles.
我知道没人窃听 来吧 你得跟我说点什么
I know nobody's listening. Come on, you've got to give me something.
跟我说说话 拜托
Talk to me, come on!
他们为什么不让你任务 派你来这儿守着
Why did they pull you off the field and put you up here?
看你的行动挺敏捷的 肯定不是因为受伤 你到底做了什么
It's not physical, with the way you've been moving, so what did you do?
拒绝任务 开始为自己着想
Turn down an assignment? Start thinking for yourself?
还是恋爱了
Fall in love?
你恋爱了
You fell in love.
(COCKS GUN)
这枪对付狼管用
It's better for wolves.
门边上有弹夹 你想拿多少就拿多少
There's an ammo box by the door, you take as much as you need.
我们谈完了
We're done talking.
你回完饭早点出发 应该能赶上
You ate, you're pulling out early. You should hit it.
好的
Okay.
-那有时间再聊 -是
-Some other time, then. -Yeah.
-谢谢 -祝你好运
-Thanks. -Good luck.
韩国 首尔
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
这是什么
What's this?
我觉得我们要把话说清楚 唐
BYER: I think that we need to clarify something here, Don.
说清楚什么
PAULSEN: Clarify What?
你一直说不能接受
You keep using the word "unacceptable"
我想知道你到底是什么意思
and I want to know exactly what you think you mean by that.
不能接受就是不能接受
"Unacceptable" means exactly that.
我不喜欢你告诉我的事
I don't like what you're telling me,
也不喜欢你的态度
I don't like how you're telling me.
我们四个任务都处于关键时期 瑞克
We're in a critical phase on four missions, Ric.
如果我们现在叫停 损失将不可估量
The intelligence loss, if we stop now, it couldn't be quantified.
其实是可以估量的
Yes, actually, it could.
你可以回到参与项目前的工作岗位
You'd be right back to where you were before we delivered the program.
别再跟我说结果行动出了问题
Don't tell me there's a problem with Outcome
因为我已经听说了
because I'd be hearing about it.
-我没说有问题 -你没说的多了
-I didn't say there was. -You're not saying much of anything.
一周一片
One pill, once a week.
每八天一次
Every eight days.
也就是说不用再吃蓝色和绿色的药了
So, no more blues and greens.
项目中每个人都在过度时期
We're transitioning everyone in the program.
你记得怎样写精确的饮食记录吧
Do you remember how to keep an accurate diet log?
记得
Yes.
你知道这些特工的功用吗
PAULSEN: Do you understand their full utility?
在一位特工卧底36个月后
We just set Iran's missile program back
我们阻止了伊朗的核计划
36 months with one deep-cover agent.
两年来 朝鲜最好的侦察行动
The best action recon out of North Korea
人员都来自结果行动
in the last two years came from Outcome.
-我很清楚 -你知道我们等了多久
-I'm fully aware of this. -Do you know how long we've waited
才能让我们的人真正打入巴基斯坦三军情报局内部
to get a real, long-term operative inside Pakistani ISI?
你这是在让我把正在执行任务的
You're asking me to wipe the most valuable
最优秀的探员都撤下来
intel-gathering assets we've ever put in the field.
我们马上就要停止运作
We're shutting things down immediately
然后把这个烂摊子收拾干净
and this contingency was covered loud and clear.
我们得好好谈谈这是怎么回事
PAULSEN: Tell me this isn't why we're having this conversation.
杰森·伯恩跑了 对吧
Jason Bourne got away, didn't he?
就是这么一回事 对吧
That's what this is all about, isn't it?
除了你的 我知道系统所有的行动
I have visibility on every action program in the system except yours.
别再跟我说我不能知道这些情况
I'm sick of hearing the reason I can't do something or see something
是因为国家研究分析集团没授权
is because it hasn't cleared the National Research Assay Group.
你怎么能这样推卸责任
Where do you pull this kind of weight?
唐 我跟你一样 是个爱国者
Don, I'm a patriot, the same as you are.
我跟你一样流血牺牲过
I bleed over this the same way you do.
但是你我分工不同
But you and I have our jobs
因为我们各有所长 都得做一些必须要做的事
because we've got the strength to do what's necessary
很抱歉 但是目前只能这样
and I'm sorry, but right now, this is it.
(PANTING)
(WHISTLE BLOWING) (GUARDS SHOUTING)
外面的暴风雪越来越大 越来越严重了
It's really coming down out there. It's getting ugly.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
也许我应该想办法快点离开暴风雪的区域 对吧
Well, maybe I should try to get ahead of it, huh?
算了吧 已经太晚了 你就待在这儿
No, it's too late for that. Just stick around.
反正我需要人帮我整理一下这地方
I need some help squaring the place away, anyway.
我不知道
Yeah, I don't know.
我早就该回去报到做检查了
I already have to do that medication write-up.
我不知道我要不要解释
I don't know if I want to have to explain
自己的行动路线 你明白我的意思吧
my itinerary as well, you know what I mean?
别担心药的事 我能帮你解决
Don't worry about the chems, I got that covered.
我去看看
I'm gonna have a look.
(VERY FAINT WHIRRING)
你听到了吗
Are you hearing that?
你在等什么吗
Are you expecting anything?
这样的天气 还不预先通知
In this weather, without a heads-up?
绝对越来越近了
Well, it's definitely getting closer.
搜到什么吗
What do you got?
没有 什么都没有
Nothing, man, I got nothing.
-这机器运作良好吗 -当然
-Is it working? -Yeah, it's working.
机器没问题 肯定是其它原因
The gear is fine. It's not the gear.
也许是来送补给的
Well, maybe it's a resupply.
昨天就来过了 这天气他们也没法着陆
They were here yesterday, and they can't land in this, anyway.
到底是谁
Who the hell is it?
不知道
I don't know.
我不知道 我们应该分头调查一下
I don't know. We should spread.
好 我在屋里待命
Yeah. Look, I'll take the nest.
-看到是什么了告诉我 好吗 -好
-Let me know when you get eyes on it, okay? -Yeah.
(GRUNTS)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
国防情报 特别行动 无人机指挥中心
弗吉尼亚州 卡森
任务完成了吗
PILOT: Is she gonna clear us here?
在暴风雪变严重之前 我要拉升飞行高度了
I'd like to get above this before it gets any sloppier.
等等 有一个…
Now, hold on. Just, there's a...
收到 单翼 我也看见了 稍等片刻
Copy, Solo, I saw it, too. Give us a minute.
明白
SOLO: Wilco.
-怎么回事 -等等 等等
-PILOT: What's the issue? -Hang on, hang on.
收到 单翼 我正在搜索
Roger, Solo. Sourcing now.
屏幕上显示仍然有一个活动的信号
It looks like there's still an active signal back there.
你说什么
Excuse me?
-是你那儿的问题还是… -是我这边的问题
-Is that on your end or is that... -SOLO: My end.
现在信号交换非常困难
We're having a hard time getting a handshake.
明白 单翼 继续转播
Roger, Solo. Holding on relay.
我以为你把导弹信号连上了呢
I thought you had them linked.
是连上了
We did.
导弹直接击中建筑物里的目标信号
They were lined up, all the way to the structure.
两个信号都很清晰 没有问题
Both targets were green, all the way in.
-是人类吗 -不知道
-SOLO: ls there a MD? -Unknown.
-是敌人吗 -不知道
-Hostile ? -Unknown.
不是卫星回声吧
OFFICER: It's not a satellite echo, is it?
不是 长官
No, sir.
她在干什么
OFFICER: What's she doing?
她正在回放
She's playing it back.
我可不能这样等她 我们得让无人机转回去
I don't want to wait on her. We're going to have to come around.
离回航安全油量还有多长时间
How far are you from bingo fuel?
还可待命20分钟
Twenty minutes on station.
最好能快点
Better get on it.
收到 单翼 但是我们得找另一条路径过去
SPEC: Affirmative, Solo, but we're gonna need another pass here.
-她知道我们什么都看不到 是吧 -查看一下
-She knows we can't see shit, right? -Check it.
收到 正在进行新配置
Roger that. New profile engaged.
我们转回去了
We're coming around now.
收到 单翼 东南偏东方向
PILOT: Roger that, Solo. East-southeast.
从山谷方向进去
Coming right back up the valley.
请求剩余燃料量 请报告你的状况
Requesting fuel graph, say your state.
离发射还有两分三十秒
PILOT: State two-plus-30 to splash.
单翼 收到 油量充足
Copy, Solo. Fuel to bingo is green.
现在提供目标方位
Sourcing target beacon now.
(RAPID BEEPING)
发生什么了
What just happened?
信号消失了 它怎么就消失了呢
It's gone. Where the hell did it go?
你说它怎么就消失了是什么意思
What do you mean, "Where did it go?"
单翼 我们这儿搜不到信号了
Solo, we are negative on that signal here.
我们搜不到第二个目标的信号了
We just lost that second beacon.
搜不到了 单翼 所有的感测器和系统都正常
Negative, negative, Solo. All sensors and systems are green.
诊断正常 飞机正常
Diagnostics are green, aircraft is green.
除了搜不到目标 一切正常
I got everything but a target here.
这不是系统问题 感测器一切正常
It is not a system issue. Sensors are good.
好吧 我们切换到红外图看看
All right, we're going to switch to IR and take a look.
收到 切换到热感图
-Roger. -Switching to thermal.
(FIRES)
单翼 给我你最后一次看到…
-Solo, can I get your last confirmed... -(THUD OVER SPEAKER)
(STATIC HISSING)
怎么回事
What the hell was that?
红冠 我们被干扰了
SOLO: Red Crown, we 're getting some music.
你撞到东西了
SPEC: You hit something.
我不这么认为 红冠 听到了吗
-I don't think so. -Red Crown, you getting this?
前面没有障碍物 什么都没有
There is nothing there. There is nothing.
到底出了什么事
What the hell is going on, here?
飞机不是除了故障 而是被击落的 他们确定吗
It didn't just go down, it was shot down? They're sure about that?
他们就是这么告诉我的
That's what I was told.
谁击落的 用什么
By Who? With What?
他们也不知道
They don't know.
他们正在定位第二个目标 飞机就被击落了
They were sourcing a second signal when it happened.
不 不 我们没时间了 我现在就要权限
DITA: No, no, no, we didn't have time. I'm calling for clearance now.
让人到大门来接我们
There's got to be someone meeting us at the gate.
他们准备好无人机了吗
They have a drone ready?
正在给它加油
They're fueling one now.
他们分析过信号了
They parsed the signal.
是艾伦·克劳斯的
It's Aaron Cross.
该死
Shit.
长官 一切准备就绪
You're all set, sir.
接近上次飞机被击落位置30度的地方
PILOT: Let's approach off azimuth, 30 degrees off our last pass.
没问题
SPEC: Good for me.
呼叫红冠 转向3-0-0
SOLO: Red Crown to contact. Three-zero-zero for 30.
就在那儿 看到信号了
SPEC: There you are. There's my signal.
单翼 信号很强
Signal is hot, Solo.
信号出现 准备行动
Signal is up and live. And here we go.
之前去哪儿了
PILOT: Where's that been?
无所谓了 我来搞定
Doesn't matter now. It's mine.
收到 单翼 信号很强
Copy, Solo. Strong signal.
这人用的是什么武器装备
What kind of weapon system is this guy operating?
他很可能有一把来福枪
He's probably got a rifle.
还是大口径来福枪
BYER: It's a high-powered rifle.
还有多久才能到
What's our time frame, here?
大约15分钟
Fifteen minutes, plus or minus.
得考虑暴风雪影响
Just trying to factor the storm.
(WOLF HOWLING)
(HOWLING CONTINUES)
(GROWLING)
收到 单翼 目标静止 准备激光锁定
SPEC: Roger, Solo. Target is static. Engaging laser now.
嘿
Hey!
(SNARLS)
滚开
Get out of here!
快点 滚开
Go on, get out of here!
滚开
Get out!
(WHIMPERS)
(BARKING)
激光已就绪
SPEC: Laser armed.
测感器和红外已定位
Sensor and thermal confirmed.
(GROWLING)
-还要多久 -30秒
-Where are we? -SPEC: Thirty seconds.
你就不该接近我
You should have left me alone.
(DRONE APPROACHING)
装载导弹
SPEC: Arming missile.
导弹发射
Missile away.
那就是他 他正在移动
There he goes, he's moving now.
动不了多久了
PILOT: Not for long.
目标已摧毁
SPEC: Target destroyed.
红冠 击中目标
SOLO: Red Crown, splash one.
收到 单翼 确认击杀成功 目标已摧毁
Copy, Solo. Kill confirmed, target destroyed.
看起来不错吧
PILOT: Looking good?
不错 看着挺干净利落的
SPEC: Looks good. Looks cold and clear.
恕我直言 长官 现在还不是最佳时机
AARON: With all due respect, sir, now is not the best time.
20分钟内 这地方就会土崩瓦解
In 20 minutes, this place is going to fall apart.
我知道 我会把握机会 我们得谈谈
BYER: I'm aware of that, I'll take the chance. We need to talk.
我要你停下来 然后转过身来
I need you to stop what you're doing and turn around.
这是命令
That's an order.
我们情报有误 是吧
We got screwed on the intel, okay?
没人知道那些人在那儿
Nobody knew those people were in there.
对我们刚才要求你做的事
It would be perfectly normal for a person to have doubts
有道德方面的顾虑是再正常不过的了
about the morality of what we just asked you to do.
你在询问我吗 长官
Is that a question, sir?
不 不是 你得把我说的话听进去
No, it's not. Tune in to what I'm trying to say to you.
你知道什么是食罪者吗
Do you know what a sin-eater is?
那就是我们 我们就是食罪者
That's what we are. We are the sin-eaters.
这意味着在这个世界中我们得把道德罪恶感
It means that we take the moral excrement that we find in this equation
深藏心底
and we bury it down deep inside of us
让人生的其它部分不受影响
so that the rest of our cause can stay pure.
这就是我们的工作
That is the job.
我们在道德上是站不住脚的 但绝对是必需的
We are morally indefensible and absolutely necessary.
你理解吗
Do you understand?
说完了吧
-Will that be all? -(EXPLOSION BOOMS)
把伤口缝好
Stitch that up.
6小时内我会把你安排到去也门的飞机上
I'm gonna put you on a plane to Yemen in six hours.
我会准备好的
I'll be ready.
(LOUD EXPLOSION)
我告诉过你她会找我们麻烦的
TERRY: I told you she'd be coming at us.
没错 泰利 我要你保持冷静 好吧
Yeah, I need you to stay calm, Terry, okay?
他们让她出席参议院听证会
They're giving her a Senate hearing.
你怎么能无视这个问题呢
How can you not see that as a problem?
她认识伯恩 她知道黑石楠计划 她也认识赫什
She knows Bourne, she knows Blackbriar, she knows Hirsch.
她对我们整个组织的事情了如指掌
She's got a handle on the whole goddamn operation.
我不理解你怎么能对这事儿这么冷静
I don't see how the hell you could be so calm about this!
好吧 她能说什么
Well, what can she say?
她能说什么
What can she say?
万一她站起来说
What if she gets up there and she says,
踩石 黑石楠 你们觉得就这些吗
"Treadstone, Blackbriar, you think that was it?
你们认为就只有一个杰森·伯恩吗
"You think that Jason Bourne was the whole story?
对不起 还有很多你们不知道的呢
"Sorry, there's a lot more going on here."
如果她告诉他们踩石计划只是冰山一角呢
What if she tells them that Treadstone was just the tip of the iceberg?
你在担心什么
BYER: Look, you want to sweat something?
还是担心结果行动吧 因为我们还没有摆脱困境
Worry about Outcome, because we're still not out of the woods.
但是就其它项目来说 她还不知道那么多呢
But as far as our other programs, she doesn't know that much.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
因为我们一直在监控她的一言一行
Because we're tapped into everything she says and does.
什么
What?
电话 邮件 汽车 住所 律师
Phones, email, cars, house, lawyer.
她接触到杰森·伯恩那刻起她就完蛋了
She was cooked the minute she hitched her wagon to Jason Bourne.
她协助并教唆了一名国际逃犯
She aided and abetted an international fugitive.
她阻止了行政机构关闭一项失控的行动
She prevented the agency from shutting down a rogue operation.
她违反了所有誓言和原则
She violated every oath and code of conduct that matters.
更离谱的是 她还把那个混蛋带回了美国
For Christ's sake, she brought the son of a bitch back to America.
现在 鬼知道她的动机是什么
Now, God knows what her motives are,
但可以肯定的是保护国家绝不是其中之一
but it's clear that protecting this country is not one of them.
这以前被称为叛国罪
That used to be called treason.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
配平方程 现在那就应该是个常数了
Even the solution here. Now, that should be coming up as a constant.
(MACHINE BEEPS)
你来啦 我不理解那些值…
There you are. I don't understand these values...
(GASPS)
天呐 不
DR. BENEZARA: My God, no!
-你听到了吗 -嗯
-Did you hear that? -Yeah.
什么声音
WOMAN: What is that?
是枪声
It's a gun.
-不 我… 不 -没错 就是枪声
-No. I... No. -Yeah. No, it was gunfire.
别 求你了 别杀我
No, please. No, no, no!
(GUN FIRES)
救命啊
Help! (POUNDING ON DOOR)
开门 他朝我们开枪了 开门
Open the door! He's shooting us! Open the door!
(ALARM CHIMING)
开门 他有枪
DR. TALWAR: Open the door! He's got a gun!
快开门
Open the door!
救命
DR. TALWAR: Help!
天呐
Oh, my God.
我们得弄一张门卡
We got to be able to get a card!
我们得快点进去
We have to be able to get in there!
发生什么事了 我们得走后门
(WHISPERING) What's happening? We gotta go for the back door.
锁着呢 他把后门锁了
It's locked. He locked the back door.
(WHIMPERING)
秋你别杀我
No, please.
他会把我们都杀掉的
He's gonna kill us all.
(SHUSHING)
-别这样 -天呐
-DR. CHANDRA: Don't do this. -Oh, my God.
让开
Move!
他朝里边所有人开枪
He's shooting everyone in there!
我需要一张红色的实验室通行卡 谁有红色的通行卡
I need a red lab access card! Who's got a red lab access card?
他们正在从楼下送一张上来
They're bringing one down from upstairs.
他们都在里边 有门卡的都在里边
They're all in there. Everyone who has one is in there.
比利 你在哪儿 我现在需要一张红卡
Billy, where are you, man? I need a red card now!
(DR. BENEZARA GROANS)
唐… 你在干嘛
Don... What are you doing?
-(GUN FIRES) -(GASPS SOFTLY)
(ALL CLAMORING)
妈的 门把手没了
Shit, the handle's off.
(GUN FIRES)
门把手没了
The handle's off!
(GRUNTS)
放下枪 快停下来 放下武器
Drop it! Stop! Drop the weapon!
放下枪 放下武器
Drop it! Drop the weapon!
(GUN FIRES)
(GASPING)
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
警方还在继续寻找
MALE ANCHOR: Investigators are still searching for some explanation
震惊全美的
behind the workplace murder-suicide
实验室自杀式枪击案背后的原因
that left another American community grieving and shocked.
警察和联邦官员
-Police and federal authorities -(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
正在仔细排查所有实验室人员…
were poring over the lab facility...
那些人现在就要见你
DNA: The boys need to see you fight away.
马上把编好的福伊特发布出去
Let's get that Foite story out there right away.
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
这些区域呢
COP: And this area, back here?
都已经变成储藏室了
That's all been converted to storage.
但在蓝图和指示牌上显示
Because it says on the blueprint, and even on the board, there,
那儿是一个体检室
that it's a medical examination suite.
我是说 你们说的健康检查是指哪方面
I mean, what kind of examinations are we talking about?
好了 我能看看你的手吗
MARTA: There we go. May I see the hand, please?
恢复情况不错
Oh, that has healed well.
知觉有损失吗
Any diminished sensation?
没有
Nope.
医生 你是要整我吗
Are you trying to put me down, doc?
恐怕那几次
I'm afraid there's been a few gaps
样本之间时间间隔有点长了 所以…
in your sample deliveries,son.
好吧
Uh-oh.
我们这回得来个全面检查
...we need a full work-up this visit.
又来一次
Another one?
为什么 因为我少抽了点血
Why? Is it 'cause I missed a blood drop?
医生 你觉得这样好吗
So, how do you think it works, doc?
我们放下一切工作
That we can just calla timeout?
就为了让你抽点血吗
Everything stops while you pull your samples?
你何不躺下放松点呢
Why don't you lie down and relax?
好吧
Yeah.
你觉得我们在外边是干什么的
What do you think that we do out there?
行了 说得够多了
Okay, that's enough information.
不 我…
No, I...
好吧 你只是个医生
Well, you're just a doctor.
你知道这儿有监控的
You know we're on camera.
真的吗
Really?
这就是你打扮得这么漂亮的原因
Is that why you make such an attractive appearance?
好了 你何不从100往回数数呢
Okay, why don't you count backward from 100, please?
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(COUNTING IN RUSSIAN)
芝加哥
马里兰州实验室枪击案 六人死亡
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
喂
Hello?
是 门应该是开着的
Yeah, the gate should be open.
朝左拐 大约半英里的路程
Bear to the left. It's about half-a-mile up.
谢谢
Thanks.
-您是希林医生吗 -没错
-Dr. Shearing? -Uh-huh.
你好 我是康妮·多德医生
Hi, I'm Dr. Connie Dowd.
-你好 你还好吗 -很好 谢谢
-Hi, how are you? -Well, thanks.
这位是莱瑞·胡珀特工
This is Special Agent Larry Hooper.
-你好 -你好
-Hello. -Hello.
请进
Please. Come in.
谢谢您的配合
DR. DOWD: Thanks for letting us come out.
真是豪华 这房子不错
It's a remarkable property. What a project.
嗯 我实在不想说这个房子
Yeah, I really don't want to talk about the house.
除非你想买它
Not unless you want to buy it.
两位请坐
Sit, I guess. Please.
好吧 你们知道的
MARTA: Just so you know, okay,
我一小时前还不知道这个会面
I didn't know anything about this meeting until an hour ago.
也没人跟我约个时间
And nobody last night said to make time
或者是选个日子等等
or pick a time, or anything like that.
所以 今天早上 我买了一张机票去看我妹妹
And then, this morning, I buy a plane ticket to see my sister
突然事态就变得像核战危机4那样了
and suddenly it's like DEFCON 4 around here.
这根本不是妄想症 好吧
And that is not paranoia, okay?
这事儿太突然了
That is pretty much directly in my face!
我很理解
DR. DOWD: Understood.
我们不该关注你吗
Should we not be paying attention?
莱瑞 你能让我们单独谈谈吗
Can you leave us alone, Larry?
听着
Look.
你刚遭遇了一段惨痛的经历
You've just been through an extremely traumatic experience.
是 你是什么医生
Yeah. Doctor of what?
哪方面的
What are you?
临床心理学
Clinical psychology.
那么你是干什么的
Oh. So, what do you do?
你给间谍做心理辅导吗
You give grief counseling to spies?
玛泰 你的权限非常特别
You have a very unusual security clearance, Marta.
你应该早就想到买了去蒙特利尔的机票
You should expect that buying a ticket
却不告诉任何人 会让有关部门非常担忧
to Montreal without telling anyone would set off some bells.
我自己已经担心得够多了 好吧
Yeah, I've got some bells of my own going off, okay?
我是说 你来是要告诉我
I mean, are you going to be the person who tells me
到底发生了什么事
What the hell is going on here,
还是仅仅想当下神秘的保姆呢
or are you just the next mystery babysitter?
你觉得呢
What do you think is going on?
我现在努力让自己不去多想
What I'm trying to do is not think.
我就是… 我不想去多想
I just... I want to stop thinking.
你跟其他人宣泄过这种情绪吗
Have you discussed those feelings with anyone else?
你妹妹 朋友
Your sister? Friends?
你是认真的吗
Are you for real?
那彼得·博伊德呢
What about Peter Boyd?
噢
Wow.
好吧
Okay.
就是说 我们什么都得说说 是吧 问什么都可以了是吧
So, we're into everything, is that it? Is anything off-limits here?
你读过你的雇佣保密合同吗
Have you ever read your employment security contract?
我读过…
Have I read my...
如果你是问我是否理解信息披露限制的话
If you're asking me whether I understand my disclosure restrictions,
我理解 我是生化学的博士
yes, I have a PhD in biochemistry
是病毒学和遗传学的博士后
with postdoctoral fellowships in virology and genetics.
我知道怎么读
I know how to read!
我不理解的是为什么我的同事
What I don't understand is why my colleague
会突然像个神经病人一样朝实验室所有人开枪
has a psychotic episode and shot everyone in the lab.
你知道我们在实验室里做什么吗
Are you aware of what we do in there?
你知道吗
Are you?
我是说 我怎么知道你有没有听这些的权限
I mean, how do I know that you're even cleared for this conversation?
你跟除了调查人员之外的任何人
Have you discussed anything to do with the incident
谈过这件事吗
with anyone other than the investigators?
彼得·博伊德八个月前就搬出去了
Peter Boyd moved out eight months ago.
我猜你也知道了
But I guess you already know that.
我当然没跟他说过
And, no, I haven't spoken to him.
你申明说你和福伊特医生除工作之外没什么关系
You stated that you and Dr. Foite had no relationship outside of work.
的确没有
None.
但在他的公寓中发现一些东西证明
There was material in his apartment that indicates he had
他对你有特殊的感情
an unusual fixation with you.
照片 分类账 他们还发现了几件衣服
Photographs, journal entries. They found several articles of clothing.
什么
What?
你拒绝过他吗
Did you ever rebuff him in any way?
没有
No.
不 不 我…
No, no, I...
我一直认为他是个同性恋
I always thought he was gay.
听着 没人说你应该为这事儿负责
Look, no one is suggesting that you're responsible for what happened.
谢谢
Oh. Thank you.
幸存者经常会有罪恶感的
Survivors often experience feelings of guilt.
当你想到他留你活口了
Those feelings can be amplified
这种感觉就会被放大
by the realization that he let you live.
他留我活口
That he let me live?
你看录像了吗
Have you seen the video?
你真的觉得就是录像中那么回事
Do you really think that's what it shows?
你一直在问错的问题
You are asking all the wrong questions!
玛泰 那我该问什么呢
What should I be asking, Marta?
有人验过福伊特医生的血了吗
Has anyone looked at Dr. Foite's blood work?
验过了吗
Have they?
我是说 那才是唯一值得调查的事情
I mean, that is the only thing that is going to make any sense, here.
他的行为…
His behavior was...
听着 在斯特里森有些项目
Look, there are projects at Sterisyn,
那些项目可以解释他为什么这样做
defense projects that could explain Why he did What he did.
那儿的人致力于研究人的行为设计
And people there are working on behavioral design.
那是设计好的行为 完全是通过神经设计
It's programmable behavior, neural design.
你理解我跟你说的吗
Do you understand what I'm telling you?
我认为他曾在实验室接触过什么东西
I think he was exposed to something at the lab.
找到了
Found it.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
那是我的枪 这到底算怎么回事
That's my gun. What the hell is this?
你有潜在的自杀危险
You're a potential suicide risk.
不 等一下 你怎么…
No. Wait a minute. How did you...
-他怎么找到的 -玛泰…
-How did he find that? -Marta...
不 不 好了 会面结束了
No, no. Okay. This meeting is now over.
-我要你们离开这儿 就现在 -玛泰…
-I want you both out of here, right now! -Marta...
不 他竟然去翻查我的房间
No! He has been snooping around my house!
玛泰 我今天是来解决问题的
Marta, I want to sign off here today!
我也想让你赶上那趟飞机
I want to let you get on that plane,
但你得配合我们
but you have got to help us out!
听着 我们来这儿是尽职责 懂吗
Look, we have got to do our job here, okay?
我们是例行公事
We have got to go through this.
我得确保我离开这儿之前你是冷静的 安全的
I need to know that you are calm and safe before I leave here
而且我得确保你在上飞机之前理解那些规则
and I need to know that you understand the rules before you get on that plane.
请…
Please, just...
请坐下 我们得把问题搞清楚
Please, sit down and let us get through our questions.
好吧
Okay.
(MARTA SCREAMS)
天呐 这是干嘛
Jesus! What is this?
-这是干嘛 -准备好了吗
-What the hell is this? -Ready?
-差不多了 -你们在干嘛
-Close. -What are you doing?
放开我
Get off me!
准备好了吗
Set?
-放开我 -准备好了
-Get the hell off me now! -Set!
-开枪 -不
-Green! -No!
(GUN FIRES)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
金
DRIVER: Gene!
有个跑到地下室了
A runner in the basement!
去看看
Go!
-康妮 -在你的右边
-Connie! -On your right.
有个女人
One. Girl.
(PANTING)
(SCREAMS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
把她找出来
Find her.
快她找出来
Find her!
(TOOL WHIRRING)
金 回答我
Gene! Talk to me!
(LOUD WHIRRING)
(WHIRRING STOPS)
嘿
Hey.
(GUN CLICKING)
除非你重装子弹 否则枪是空的
Unless you reloaded, the gun is empty.
看着我
-(GUN CLICKING) -Look, look.
希林医生 是我
Dr. Shearing, it's me.
-我不会伤害你的 好吧 -你怎么…
-I'm not here to hurt you, okay? -How did you...
-是你 -是的 小点声
-That was you! -Yes. Shh!
听我说 你想活命吗
Listen to me. Do you want to live?
看着我 你想活命吗
Look at me. Do you want to live?
-你想活命吗 -嗯
-Do you want to live? -Yes.
那好 扔掉这把枪
Good. Let go of this gun.
-这怎么可能 -扔掉它
-How is this possible? -Let go.
拿着这把
Take this.
好样的
Good.
现在 我要你按我说的做
Now, I need you to do exactly what I say.
-这怎么可能 -听我说 听好我说的话
How is this possible? Listen to me. Exactly what I say.
-懂了吗 -嗯
-Understand? -Yeah.
好
Good.
(DOOR CLOSES)
嘿 医生 把表还给我
AARON: Hey, doc? I need my watch.
医生 把表还给我
Doc, I need that watch!
这房间里有药吗
Are there chems in this house?
那个项目用的药
Program medication.
他们都死了吗
Are they all dead?
嗯 都死了
Yeah, they're dead.
看着我 听我说 你这儿有那个项目用的药吗
Look at me. Look at me. Do you have program medication here?
什么
What?
绿色和蓝色的药 你这儿有吗
Chems. Greens, blues. Do you have them here?
-没有 没有 -没有
-No, no. -No?
-这儿 没有 -就这儿
-Here? No, no. -Here.
那哪儿有 你把药放在哪里了
Where, then? Where do you have them?
-哪儿 -你把药放在哪里了
-Where? -Where do you keep the theme?
我不知道
I don't know.
希林医生 药在哪儿 我需要那些药
Dr. Shearing, where are the chems? I need the chems!
我明白 但是我不知道
I understand, but I don't know.
(STUTTERING)
不是… 我们是做病毒控制的
It's not something... We do virology control.
所以 发生的一切…
So, all of that happens...
我们是没有药的
We don't have medication.
如果我有的话 肯定会给你的
If I had any, I would give it to you.
行 听我说
Okay, listen to me.
我们有不到8分钟的时间离开这里 好吗
We have less than eight minutes to clear out of here, okay?
-恩 -很好
-Yes. -Good.
因为下一个穿过那扇门的人
Because the next thing coming through that door
就是来杀我们的
is going to wipe us out.
(RADIO CRACKLES)
我能了解一下情况吗
Can I get a sitrep, here?
听到请回复 莱瑞
If you can hear me, pick up, Larry.
莱瑞 请回复
(OVER RADIO) Larry, pick up.
抱歉 信号不好
AARON: Hey. Sorry about the tran.
我们这儿的频率是多少
What's our frame-rate, here?
康妮说大约是10 刚刚完成任务
Connie says about 10. Just wrapping up.
告诉她小心点 好吗
Tell her we need a heads-up. Okay?
收到
Copy that.
嘿
Hey.
最好是由你来动手
It's probably better you did this.
(LOUD EXPLOSION)
(SIREN WAILING)
我们去哪儿
Where are we going?
琼 你的名字叫琼·梦露 说说看
June. Your name is June Monroe, say it.
-琼·梦露 -再说一遍
-June Monroe. -Say it.
我是琼·梦露
June Monroe.
现在选个居住地
Now pick a place you lived.
你上一个住的地方 选个你知道的
The last place you lived. A place you know.
-贝塞斯达 -好 贝塞斯达是你的常住地
-Bethesda. -Bethesda, that's where you live.
任何人问起 就说你是来自贝塞斯达的琼·梦露
Anybody asks, you're June Monroe from Bethesda.
你丢了钱包 我载你回家
You lost your wallet. I'm driving you home.
我名字叫詹姆斯 詹姆斯和琼 记住了吗
My name is James. James and June, you got it?
-记住了 -好的
-Yeah. -Okay.
那是你的真名吗
Is that your name?
詹姆斯吗
James?
不是 什么 你不知道我的名字吗
No. What? You don't know my name?
你们都叫我什么呢 我抽血的血样上面 你写了什么
What do you call me? What do you put on my blood work?
五
Five.
五 五号
Five? The number five?
你知道我们见过多少次了吗
Do you know how many times we've met?
一共十三次
Thirteen.
过去四年里体检了十三次
Thirteen exams over the last four years.
你却一直用号码称呼我
And that's what I get, a number?
好吧 五号
Number Five. Okay.
什么五号呢 我们有多少人
Five of what, then? How many are we?
项目参与者
Program participants?
你就是那样称呼我们的
That's what you call us?
原来有九个 后来变成六个了
There were nine. Then six.
参与者
Participants.
你是怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
你认为呢
Well, what do you think?
他们会杀光我们
They're going to kill all of us
然后会放过你们吗
and then just leave you guys alone?
你觉得你同事只是发疯了吗
You think your colleague just went crazy?
你是那么想的吗
Is that what you think?
-我什么也没想 -他们紧逼他 再让他爆发
-I didn't think anything. -They wound him up and set him loose.
我真的不知道发生了什么
I really have no idea What is going on.
情况就是 他们要终止整个项目
What's going on is they're shutting the Whole thing down.
他们是谁
Who is "they"?
不知道… 在你家的人是谁
I don't know... Who were the people at the house?
不 以前都是你在问问题 好吗
No,no,no,no. You had your turn, okay?
从我们遇见那天起 你就在询问我 检查我 抽我的血
You've been bleeding and scoping and scraping me since the day we met.
现在轮到我了 换我问问题了 懂吗
It's my turn, now. I'm asking the questions, you got it?
我需要药 懂吗 我需要项目用的药
I need program meds, okay? I need program meds.
你们把药存在哪儿了
Where do you keep the theme?
已经告诉过你了 我没有药
I don't have any. I've already told you.
-我们没有药 -胡说
-We don't have them. -Bullshit.
都是瞎话
Bullshit. It's bullshit.
我没有药
I don't have any!
那你什么都不知道吗 你就是去帮忙的
So, you don't know anything? You're just the help?
那就是你住大房子 有保密权限的原因 对吗
That's why you have the big house and the security clearance, right?
这也是他们要拼了命杀你的原因
That's why they're trying so hard to kill you,
就因为你什么也不知道
because you don't know anything.
我只知道我的工作 哪就是科学
I know my job, which is science.
我不知道出了实验室你们是做什么的
I don't know what you do when you leave the lab.
-我们都不知道 -已经四年了呀
-None of us do! -For four years!
听着 我要下车 请你停车好吗
Look, I want to get out! Would you please stop the car?
你不会那么天真吧
You can't be that naive.
-你能让我下车吗 -你不会那么天真的
-Would you let me out the car? -There's no way you're that naive!
你想下车 走吧 快点 下车
You want out? Get out. Go on, get out.
你没有药 也不知道药在哪儿
You don't have any chems. You don't know where they are.
你什么也不知道 没关系 下车吧
You don't know anything. That's fine. Just get out.
但你是有计划的 是吗
But you got a plan, right?
哦 当然了 你是医生嘛
Yeah, of course you do. You're a doctor.
一切问题你都解决了 不是吗
You've got this all worked out, don't you?
你接下来怎么办
What are you going to do?
嗯 接下来你怎么做
Huh? What are you going to do?
你不能 又不会单独跑路
You can't run, not alone. You don't know how.
当然你没法躲起来了
You certainly can't hide.
由于他们手头资源丰富 他们迟早会抓到你的
Not from people like this, with the resources they have.
你都逃不过日落 那么还剩下什么呢
You won't make it to sundown. So, what does that leave you?
你当然可以去找媒体 将一切公之于众
You can go public, sure. You can go loud.
给你妹妹打电话 因为那能解决问题
Call your sister, because that worked out well for you.
打给你的前任室友
Call some ex-roommate.
打给个在华盛顿邮报有门路的家伙
Calla guy that knows a guy at The Washington Post.
把消息放到网上 知道吗
Put it online. 'Cause you know what?
你把我甩了 就只有这一条出路了
You blow me off, that's the only play you've got.
但你最好先问问自己
But you'd better ask yourself this.
你公之于众的速度和力度够不够
Could you ever say it loud enough or fast enough
能否让他们谨言慎行 不再来杀你
that they'd be too afraid to finish what they've started?
现在我有个计划 而且没那么复杂
Now, I've got a plan, and it's just not that complicated.
我就等着下一个来杀你的人
What I'm going to do is wait for the next person to show up to kill you.
也许他们能帮我呢
Maybe they can help me.
所以快走吧
So, go for it.
我没得选 我得离开那儿
I had no choice. I had to get out of there.
不 我得离开那儿
No, I had to get out of there!
不 没有人 我不知道
No, nobody. I have no idea.
你得明白结果项目里的所有试验
You have to understand. All the work at Outcome, all those tests,
体能消耗速度 剂量变化 肌肉组织的力量
the burn rates, dosage panels, tissue stress.
我是说 这一切都是我们在控制你们体内的化学元素
I mean, that is us tuning chemistry.
我们不能添加新的元素 这会让事情恶化
We don't fabricate anything. That happens downstream.
等等恶化是什么意思
Wait. What's that mean, "downstream"?
意思就是你需要活病毒来催化粘附
It means you need live virus to seed adhesion.
培养菌是活性极高
Cultures are highly reactive.
必须在现场处理 我们不会在这做的
You have to process on-site and we would never do it here.
好的 现场在哪儿 在哪里
Okay. On-site, where? Where?
病毒保存的地方吗
Where do we hold the virus?
是的
Yes!
好了 我们不能开车去
Well, we can't drive there.
-在哪里 -马尼拉
-Where is it? -Manila.
在菲律宾
The Philippines.
你现在还剩多少药
Where do you stand with your dosage?
我还有300毫克的蓝色药片
I have 300 milligrams of blues.
都不够一天的药量
It's not even enough for another day.
我已经51小时没服用绿色药片了
I haven't had a full green in 51 hours,
奇怪的是我竟然没觉得身体有任何退化
which is strange because I don't feel physically degraded.
但等着瞧吧
But we'll see.
等一下 等等
Wait, wait, wait.
你刚刚说你还在服用绿色药片
Did you just say you're still taking greens?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
去年你就已经接受病毒注射 不用再吃体能药了
You were viraled off physical medication last year.
什么
What?
天呐 8个月前他们让所有人都不用服用绿色药片了
Jesus. They viraled everyone off greens eight months ago.
他们把活病毒注射到你体内
They infected you with live virus,
也就是说你生理上是稳定的
which means that, physically, you're stable.
你不用再服用绿色药片
You don't need to take greens.
它们早就在你体内了
They locked it in.
现在的体能增强都是永久性的
Any physical enhancement is now permanent.
是你给我注射的吗
So, you infected me?
什么时候
When was this?
是我生病的时候吗
Is this when I was sick?
那个神秘的流感疫苗 是你动手的吗
The mystery flu? That was you?
不 不是我给你注射的
Well, it wasn't me. I didn't do it.
是你 那是故意的 对吧
That was you. That was on purpose, right?
我差点死掉
When I almost died.
对不起 但那不是我
I'm sorry, but it wasn't me.
那我为什么还在服用绿色药片呢
Why am I still taking green pills, then?
不知道 我以为你已经停止服用了呢
I don't know. I thought you had stopped.
我为什么要问你呢
Why am I asking you anything?
或者用皮带拴住我们 对吗
Or to keep us on a leash, right?
真是这样吗 要控制我们
Is that it? To keep a hold on us?
让我们产生依赖性
To keep us dependent?
谁跟你说可以这样的
Who tells you that this is okay?
没有人… 我做了…
No one... I do...
谁说可以这样的
Who says it's okay?
我做了调查
I do research.
我只管设计和调查 但我不管理药物
I design, I survey. I don't administer meds.
我不制定政策
I don't make policy!
不 你是给枪上膛的
No, you just load the gun.
天呐
Oh, God.
听着 我就是为了搞科研
Look, I was there for the science.
我们都是搞科研的
We were all there for science.
我知道你不在乎 但我也牺牲了好多
And I know you don't care, but I made a huge sacrifice.
我既不能发表论文 也不能去交流会
I couldn't publish, I couldn't conference.
我不能告诉任何人那些成就是我做的
I couldn't tell a single person What it was I did.
但我以为这是在帮助我的国家 我也知道那是…
But I thought I was helping my country, and I know that's...
告诉我 你也可以让我脱离蓝色药片
Tell me you can viral off blues.
你能让我脱离蓝色药片吗
Can you viral off blues?
理论上来说是可以的
Theoretically, yes.
好
Yeah.
-药片能造成短时的增强 -好的
-Pills allow for temporary adhesion. -Okay.
要让它们永久存在于你体内 就需要活的培养细胞 活病毒
To lock it in, you need live culture. Live virus!
你知道该怎么做
You know how to do that.
你知道怎么做吗
Do you know how to do that?
-是的 -很好
-Yes. -Okay.
好 但我要告诉你 东西在地球的另一端
Yes, but I told you, it's on the other side of the planet.
嗯 猜猜我们要去哪儿
Well, guess where we're going?
欢迎来到华盛顿 欢迎来到精炽制药集团总部
WOMAN: Welcome to Washington. Welcome to Candent World Headquarters.
启明有限责任公司
纽约 伯尔尼 新加坡 华盛顿
启明健康
启明财团
启明研究所
启明定制服务
我们想确保在接下来的几天时间
We want to make sure that over the next few days
你们有机会接触到让斯特里森·莫兰塔公司
you have a chance to connect with the people who have made Sterisyn Morlanta
成为精炽制药集团骄傲的精英们
the crown jewel in the Candent group of companies.
预期本月新药拉奎尔和斯普索林
Final Phase 3 testing approval is expected this month
将通过第三阶段的最终测试
for both reQuiel and Supressolyn.
能按时完成测试让我们信心倍增 我们还要做好准备
Confidence is high that we're coming in on schedule, and we want to be ready.
我们知道市面上是急切盼望这些新药的
We know the market is eager.
我们也知道 在全球 这种…
We know, globally, the kind of...
我究竟还有什么是不知道的
What the hell don't I know about this?
你是指责我吗
You're directing that at me?
我们派过去的可是精英小组
That was a D-Trac team we sent in there.
我不知道那是什么意思
I don't know what that means.
意思就是他们对自己的工作很在行
It means they're good at what they do.
有人告诉我 他们失踪了
I was told that they were missing.
他们不只是失踪
They don't just go missing.
关于这个女人 你隐瞒了什么
What didn't you tell us about this woman?
没什么 她就是她 没什么好说的
Nothing. She is who she is. There's nothing to tell.
你到处审查她
You vetted her up and down.
那我们到底在看什么呢
Then what the hell are we looking at?
她有把注册手枪
INGRAM: She has a registered gun.
她加入时就知道了
TURSO: They knew that going in.
她有建筑许可
She's got building permits.
有丙烷 焊接罐 也许还有流弹
Propane, welding tanks. A stray bullet?
你想继续猜吗
You want to keep guessing?
我们得赶到那儿
We've got to get in there.
现场还有一堆人在等我呢
I've got a dozen people waiting on the perimeter.
我们还没控制现场
We don't control the site?
还没有
DITA: Not yet.
现在有概念了吗
Getting the picture now?
好了 住口
Okay, stop!
我不能在这继续进行
I can't run this from here.
我需要一个应急办公室 还有集成网格和通讯
I need a crisis suite. I need integrated grids and comms.
所有都要
I need all of it.
问国家安全局 五角大楼 或者自由十字要人
NSA, or Pentagon, or Liberty Crossing.
我不管 给我一队人马
I don't care, just get me something now.
整理你们的代码和硬盘
Pack up your codes and your drives,
还有其他需要的东西
and whatever else you're going to need.
我们要转移到应急办公室去
We're going to move and we're going to stay there.
蒂塔 我该怎么解释那栋房子的火灾 那附近都是居民
Dita, how am I putting a net over that house? There's locals all over it.
就说是病菌问题
We go with germs.
她带走了工作的样品
She took samples from work.
病原体还有病毒 这可是国家安全
Pathogens, viruses. It's national security.
很好 我喜欢 这有作用
Good, okay, I like that, it plays.
快点 把这个说辞发布出去
Now, get it out there, get it out there.
快点 我们动身了 每个人都那好装备 好吗
Come on, let's go, let's go. Everybody find another gear, okay?
因为我想在20分钟内赶到那里
Because I want to be out of here in 20.
那么 就说你想改变人体结构
MARTA: So, let's say you want to change the human body.
你想修正一个错误
You want to fix a mistake.
你想修复 想改善
You want to repair something, improve something.
嗯 如果你要重组人类遗传物质
Well, if you're going to reprogram human genetic material,
就需要个运输系统 而没什么比病毒更有效
you need a delivery system, and nothing works better than virus.
就像个手提箱
It's like a suitcase.
你把基因突变包在里面
You pack in genetic mutation,
感染身体和向量 并上载到目标细胞内
infect the body and the vector unloads into the target cells.
但要让它在你想要的地点 以你想要的方式感染
But getting it where you want it, how you want it,
才是问题所在
is the nightmare.
除非你有病毒受体影射图
Unless you have a map.
1985年在迪克里克港有起严重事故
There was this terrible accident at Fort Detrick in 1985.
5个调研人员在实验室死亡 这真是个灾难
Five researchers dropped dead in the lab, andit was such a catastrophe
他们把丹·希尔科特从斯坦福大学
that they brought in Dan Hillcott
带过去评估损失
from Stanford to assess the damage.
他到了那里 意识到在那下面
He got in there and he realized that, underneath it all,
病毒受体影射领域的突破令人难以置信
was this incredible breakthrough in viral-receptor mapping.
他有了那个映射
He had a map.
我们在两种不同染色体中
You've had some very minor alterations
做了非常微小的变化
made to two different chromosomes.
绿色药片控制体能部分
The green side, the physical side,
在你的线粒体蛋白质摄取中
is nothing more than a 1.5 percent rise
上升幅度不会超过1.5%
in your mitochondrial protein uptake.
但达到了1.5%
But with 1.5 percent,
你就会看到细胞移动速度
you see this immediate increase in cellular tempo,
肌肉功效 充氧作用的增强…
muscle efficiency, oxygenaflon_.
那蓝色药片呢
And the blue side?
是智力方面的 当然不仅仅如此
Intelligence, obviously, but it's more than that.
它能控制神经的再生和弹性
It's neural regeneration and elasticity.
感官功能 疼痛抑制
Sensory function. Pain suppression.
这是整个基因定位史上
It's the most exciting development in genomic targeting
最让人兴奋的突破了
in the history of the science.
天呐
My God.
嘿 我怎么把71号监视器的内容上载到大屏幕
Hey, how do I get monitor 71 up on the big screen?
来了
Coming up.
找到了一具尸体
They found a body.
他们确认是女人 但不是玛泰·希林
They're pretty sure it's a woman, and it's not Marta Shearing.
还找到了军人身份识别牌
They found dog tags.
他们认为她是被枪杀的
They think she was shot.
嘿
Hey.
玛泰 我…
Marta, I...
你不能给任何人打电话
You can't call anyone.
那些关心你的人肯定以为你已经死了
There are people that care about you that think you're dead.
而你什么也不能做
And there's nothing you can do about it.
你联系过的人都会成为他们的目标
Anyone you contact becomes a target.
所以 你得抛开任何正常的情绪反应
So, you need to put aside any normal emotional response that you have.
我们现在唯一的优势 就是他们以为我们俩消失了
The only edge we've got right now is they think we're both gone.
好吗
All right?
好的
All right.
那么
So,
你看看这个吧
you're going to want to go through this.
就是熟悉一下
You know, just be familiar with it.
琼·梦露
June Monroe.
琼·梦露是谁
Who is June Monroe?
就是你
You are.
你认识她吗
Do you know her?
不再认识了
Not anymore.
为什么你想保持体能智力增强的模式
Why do you have to stay enhanced?
对你为什么这么重要吗
Why is it so important to you?
过来
Come here.
陨落的英雄
一等兵 肯尼斯·J·基德森
家乡 美国 内华达州 雷诺市
年龄 26岁
殁于 2003年11月17日
事故 在拉马迪进行护送任务时遭遇炸弹袭击而牺牲
这是什么
What is this?
这是我
This was me.
曾经的我
Was.
我的军队招募员
My army recruiter
想要达到他的配额
was looking to make his quota.
他在我的智力评分上增加了12分
He added 12 points to my IQ.
增加12分刚好达到最低标准
Twelve points to make the minimum.
玛泰 你见过认知退化吗
You ever seen a cognitive degrade, Marta?
感官退缩吗 你这么做过吗
Sensory withdrawal? You ever do that?
不给他们吃蓝色药片 看着他们认知迅速退化
Pull someone's blues and watch them drop off their meds?
没有
No.
因为他们训练时描绘了相当美好的情景
Because they paint a pretty graphic picture in training.
还有很长时间药效才会减弱
Hell of along way to fall.
如果我不坚持住 我们就逃不掉了
If I can't keep it together, we won't make it.
-他们相信了 -谁
-They bit. -Who?
华盛顿邮报
Washington Post.
我们刚查到封邮件
We just flagged an email.
他们会报道实验室危险物品
They're going with the story about the possible theft
失窃的那个说辞了
of the dangerous materials from the lab.
他们相信了 连罪名都已经定好了
Wow, they took it. They already flagged a DWI conviction.
真方便
That's convenient.
找到了另一具尸体 是我们的人
They found another body. One of ours.
他们在拾满地的弹壳
They're picking up shell casings all over the place.
我觉得你的医生不在那
I don't think your doctor's in there.
(WINDING FLASH MECHANISM)
(SHUTTER CLICKS)
请出示登机牌和证件
Boarding pass and ID, please.
-谢谢 -多谢
-Thank you. -Thank you.
请出示登机牌和证件
Boarding pass and ID, please.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
你在哪儿
Where are you?
我就在你后面 别转身
AARON: I'm right behind you. Don't turn around.
你就一直待在那儿
You're going to stay right here
到登机的时候再走 懂吗 你做得很好
until it's time to board, okay? You're doing great.
你看到右边的走廊了吗
You see that corridor on your right?
你可以找一个走这条走廊的人
You're gonna want to find somebody
然后跟着走过去
who's walking that way and just tag along.
一直往前走 低下头
Keep moving, keep your head down,
我们飞机上见
and I'll see you on the plane.
艾伦
Aaron?
喂
Hello?
这条线索非常清晰
The trail is definitive and fresh.
犬队从她的房子一直追踪她
The canine team tracked her from her house
通过这段树木茂盛的区域 到这个小停车场结束
through this wooded area, ending here, at this little parking lot.
她也许是事先准备好了车 或者是有人来接她走
Either she had a car waiting for her, or somebody picked her up.
街上有摄像头 但什么都没拍下
There are security cameras on the street, but there's nothing back here.
肯定有卫星录像
There's got to be satellite footage.
马里兰在美国不是很有价值的监控目标
Maryland's not exactly a high-value U.S. target.
会有很多天气的图片
There'll be plenty of weather imaging,
但我们要找得更广一点
but we're gonna have to swing a little wider
找能放大图像的实时监控录像
to find something real-time that's enhanceable.
我们正在联系国外的资源 还需要一小时
We're draining some foreign platforms. We need about an hour.
得了吧 她靠自己是做不到的
Come on, she's not pulling this off on her own.
到底是谁在帮她
Who the hell is helping her?
接下来一小时 我们在法院
MALE ANCHOR: We'll find out more in the next hour,
会带来进一步报道
while we are currently in court.
现在交回给简
Now back to Jenn.
今天早晨 联邦调查局确认阿尔伯特·赫什医生
JENN: The FBI this morning confirmed reports that Dr. Albert Hirsch
在华府酒店死于心脏衰竭
died of heart failure in a Washington, DC. hotel.
赫什医生于昨日在出席
Dr. Hirsch had been expected to testify yesterday
参议院情报委员会之前已出庭作证
before a Senate Intelligence committee.
特别委员会正在调查这起事件
That select committee is investigating links
与中情局踩石计划的崩溃
between a troubled CIA program known as Treadstone
以及杰森·伯恩之间的联系
and this man, Jason Bourne.
警方和联邦官员正在搜寻伯恩
Police and federal officials are searching for Bourne
怀疑他和近期纽约和伦敦的枪击案有关
in connection with recent shootings in New York and in London.
赫什医生已和司法部门合作
Dr. Hirsch had been cooperating with the Justice Department
在事件发生时也受到了监管保护
and was in protective custody at the time of the incident.
昨晚 委员会发言人表示
A committee spokesman told reporters last night
听证会将被暂时推迟
that the hearings will be postponed temporarily
他们将评估失去医生的…
as they evaluate the loss of Doctor...
嗨 伙计们
FLIGHT ATTENDANT: Hi, folks.
只是提醒大家在起飞和着陆过程中 要保持过道畅通
Just going to remind you to keep the aisles clear
要保持过道畅通
for any baggage during takeoff and landing.
-借过 -谢谢
-Excuse me. -Thank you.
不好意思 先生
Pardon me, sir.
先生 需要帮您找到座位吗
Sir, do you need help finding your seat?
-先生 -不 我找到了
-Sir? -No, I got it.
看到这两片阴影了吗 一个是她 这是在停车场
You see those two shadows? One of them is her. That's the parking lot.
有人停下 来了一辆车
One of them stops. Here comes the car.
-这是从哪儿来的 -用加拿大林业卫星弄到的
-Where is this from? -DITA: It's a Canadian forestry satellite.
另一个人上了车 他们就离开了
INGRAM: Here comes the other one into the car, and there they go.
-在哪儿 -他们往东面走了
-Where? -DITA: We lose them east.
我们只能提取两公里以内的画面
Our window drops out about two miles up the road.
但我们已经有了轮廓
But we've got the silhouette.
我们已经截取了监控录像 可以分发出去
We've got surveillance footage, racked and ready to go.
我们要划分小组 找到这辆车 然后找到他们的线索
We're going to split teams, find this car and link up a trail.
还让他们领先了17小时
With a 17-hour head start?
她到底能去哪儿
Where the hell can she go?
我们正在找一辆2002年款的别克拉赛博车
MAN 1: We're looking for a Buick LeSabre 2002.
我有美国特工部和国土安全局发的通缉令
I've got an NIA/Homeland warrant, that's Why.
-把你有的资料都给我们… -车上有两名乘客
-MAN 2: Well, you give us what you have... -MAN 3: Two passengers.
是一辆02年款的紫红色拉赛博车 从马里兰州里斯本西部出发
It's an '02 burgundy LeSabre starting west from Lisbon, Maryland.
收费站 高速公路出口 休息站
Tolls, exits, service stations.
我要所有监控录像
Give me every camera you've got.
我在列表里看到有联邦调查局的摄像头
I'm seeing an FBI camera bin on my list here.
不 只要道路监控录像
No, no. Traffic only.
里斯本北部 里-斯-本
West, Lisbon. L-I-S-B-O-N.
没错 那些我全要 再加上收费站的监控录像 全都给我
Yes, we want all of that and the toll cams. We want everything.
我们要收集所有的监控录像 只要有匹配车辆的都传过来
We'll take them all. Whatever hits you have, send them on.
我们会进一步分类
We will work on sorting them out.
特拉华州 威尔明顿
DITA: Wilmington, Delaware.
这就是我们要找的拉赛博车 监控录像里可以看到它驶入建筑物
This is our car, the LeSabre. We see it coming into the structure.
往下走 绕到后面 然后停在了这儿
It goes under, comes back around, and it parks here.
没有再开出来
But it doesn't come out.
这是内部监控录像 车停下四分钟后拍到的
This is inside. It's four minutes after arrival.
是她
It's her.
知不知道她在做什么
Do we know what she's doing?
她在拍护照照片
She was having her passport picture taken.
菲律宾 马尼拉
查以下机场 洛根 哈特福德 拉瓜迪亚 肯尼迪 费城 纽瓦克
DITA: Logan, Hartford, LaGuardia, Kennedy, Philly, Newark,
杜勒斯 里根
Dulles, Reagan.
我们从昨天早上的监控录像查起 这是我们的切入点
We start with yesterday morning, that is our wedge.
排查完这段时间 就能赶上他们
We clear that, and then we move up the clock.
她问你要不要哈特福德机场的监控 她能弄到
She wants to know if you want Hartford, because she can get it.
蓝色外套 坐第二排 背着个红包
Blue coat, second row. She's got a red bag.
哪个 我这里看到四个
Which one? I have four.
我有运输安全管理局授权 编号为16912
All right, I have TSA Authorization 1, 6, 9 and 12.
我要这些机场所有离港航班的信息
Airports given, all departures.
没错 先给我国际航站楼的
Yes, the international terminal first.
马上就到了
We're almost there.
看看报亭的画面
DITA: So, check out the news stand.
就是这个
There.
我不确定是她
BYER: I don't know.
洛根机场查到了可疑对象 但她带着孩子
Logan has a face we need to look at, but there's kids.
等等 等会儿再说
BYER: Hang on, hang on, hang on. Hang on.
停
Stop.
这是哪儿
Where is this?
-肯尼迪机场 -好
-Kennedy. -Okay.
我从没在晚上来过这儿 不知道这时候的规矩
I've never been here at night. I don't know the rules.
根本没有规矩 懂吗
There are no rules, okay?
自然一点 走吧
We belong here. Come on.
你好
Hey, how are you?
晚上好
Good evening.
我和希林医生要进去打开实验室
Dr. Shearing and I are here to open up the lab, please.
-头儿 -有什么事
-Sir? -What's all this?
嗨 你好
Hi, how are you?
希林医生 你好
Dr. Shearing! Dr. Shearing.
我是约瑟夫呀
Hey, it's me, Joseph.
约瑟夫
Joseph!
你好 过得好吗
Hello, how are you?
我很好
I'm good, I'm good.
-欢迎你回来 -谢谢
-Welcome back. -Thanks.
真是抱歉 我的名单上没写你今天回来
I'm sorry. I just don't have you on my list arriving.
那是因为我们改了行程
That's because we had to change our schedule.
没错 赶了早一班的航班
Yeah, we took an earlier flight.
约瑟夫 我是布朗德基医生 很高兴认识你
Joseph, I'm Dr. Brundage, by the way. It's nice to meet you.
彼此比你 但布马洛医生现在不在 他去新加坡了
Pleased to meet you, too, but Dr. Pumaloy is not here, he went to Singapore.
昨天刚出发的
He just left yesterday.
他的助手也都回去了 都没人告诉我您要来
The girls have gone home. No one told me anything.
没关系 我明白
Right. Well, I understand.
听着 我们只这儿待一周时间
Well, look, we're going to be here all week,
还有很多工作要做
and we have a lot of work to do,
所以我们得今天就进实验室
so we need to get in there tonight
做好准备工作 懂吗
and get things started, okay?
当然可以 只是…
Yeah, of course, it's just that...
你可以打电话给布马洛医生核实一下
You can call Dr. Pumaloy if you want.
我可不想让你左右为难
I just don't want to put you on the spot.
不用打电话了
No, we don't have to do that.
太棒了
Okay, great.
就你们两个人吗
It's just the two of you?
没错
Yeah.
对 没错
Yes, correct.
没错
Correct.
好 我不挂
Yes, I will hold.
快点 把画面放到大屏幕上
Get it up there. Put that up on the big screen.
对 我听着呢
Yes, I'm here.
很好 在哪儿
Good. Where?
请你立刻传一份旅客名单给我
I need an immediate upload on that passenger manifest.
我知道 她就在旁边 我让她接电话
I know. Here she is, I'm putting her back on.
是马尼拉 她搭美航167航班去了马尼拉
Manila. She took American 167 to Manila.
四十五分钟前抵达的
She landed 45 minutes ago.
艾伦
Aaron.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
飞机上一共有243名乘客
BYER: There's 243 people on that plane.
我们现在得逐一排查
We're going to scope every one of them right now.
挑一个喜欢的下载下来
So, pick a face that you like, pull it down,
如果不是他们就直接删除
and deselect it if you've cleared it.
如果发现有任何不对劲的地方
If there is anything that smells wrong to you,
哪怕只有头发丝那么一点
if there's a hair out of place that you don't like,
就不要删除
you do not clear it.
做上标记传给蒂塔 我们会再核查一遍
You flag it and you send it over to Dita and we'll check it out.
我们得登陆同一个平台 就是国土安全局9.5号平台
We have to be working off the same grid. That's Homeland 9.5.
如果你无法登录 请举手
If you don't pull that access, raise your hand,
哈迪上校会过去帮你解决技术问题
Colonel Hardy's going to come over and sort you out.
就是这儿了 对吧
So, this is it, huh?
没错
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
这到底是怎么回事 泰利
What the hell are we into, Terry?
我不知道
I don't know.
那是你的管辖范围 到底出了什么事
It's your shop. What is going on over there?
要我说什么 我什么都不知道
What did I say? I don't know.
她到那里去了多少次
Well, how many trips has she made over there?
-五次还是六次 记不清了 -为什么要去菲律宾
Five, six, I don't know. Why the Philippines?
嘿 快过来 快
Hey,hey,hey!
13排B座 卡尔·D·布朗德基
INGRAM: Seat 13-B. Karl D. Brundage, 13-B.
过来支援的人员请离开
I need support staff to clear the room.
快点 立刻出去
Stand up and walk, now.
杰克 凯西 快点 我们走
Jack, Cathy, move! Let's go.
他到底是谁
TURSO: Who the hell is he?
他是结果行动的特工
BYER: He's an Outcome agent.
他是5号特工
That's Outcome 5.
他们没死 我以为他们都死了
TERRY: They're not dead? I thought they were dead!
没错 他本来应该已经死了
BYER: Yeah, he's supposed to be dead.
-他去那儿要干什么 -我不知道
-TURSO: Then what's he doing there? -BYER: I don't know.
他在找药
VENDEL: He's looking for meds.
什么
TURSO: What?
他们用的药就是从那儿来的 他还能去干嘛
That's where the chems come from. What else would he be doing?
她肯定是在帮他
INGRAM: She's got to be helping him.
怎么帮 这怎么可能
TURSO: But how? How is that possible?
我不知道 但也不在乎
BYER: I don't know how. I don't care.
他还活着 他们去了菲律宾
He's alive, they're there.
过程已经不重要了 对吧
"How" doesn't really matter, does it?
我们现在唯一的任务就是解决这件事情
The only mission we've got now is to drop a bag over this.
他要找的药到底在不在那儿
Are the drugs he's looking for there, or not?
天呐 我不… 泰利 药在那儿吗
Jesus, I don't... Terry?
不 那儿什么都没有
No. No, there's nothing there.
我们已经有16个星期没有运输药物过来了
We haven't made a run in 16 weeks.
另外 在那儿也没有任何存货
Besides, we wouldn't store the pills there, anyway.
那边只是一个加工工厂
It's basically a kitchen.
我们调整配比 需要的时候在那儿制造一批
We tweak the recipe and we bake up a batch when we need it.
那他们到底去那儿干嘛
Then what the hell are they doing?
原始病毒在那儿
The stems are there.
她想帮他脱离药物
She's going to try to viral him out.
谢谢
Thank you.
-麦克 -什么事
-Mack. -Yeah?
你好 我是工厂办公室的麦克
Plant office, Mackie speaking.
麦克先生 我是泰伦斯·沃德
TERRY: Mr. Mackie, this is Terrance Ward.
精炽制药公司的高级副总裁
I'm the Senior Vice-President for Candent Precision Metrics.
-我是从马里兰州的总公司打来的 -您好 先生
-I'm calling from Maryland. -Yes, sir.
我们发现了工厂的安全隐患
We have a potential security incident.
我刚在公司内网上发布了两张照片
I just posted two photographs on the company network.
我想知道 这两个人有没有试图…
I need to know if either of these two people have tried to enter...
我们已经在查了
Yeah, we're on it.
你说什么
Excuse me?
已经在查了 我们刚才还在考虑要把这情报汇报给谁
Yeah, we're on the case. We're just here now trying to figure out who to call.
我们的门卫放行了两名医生
Our gatehouse just passed in two doctors.
我觉得其中那个女人
I think one of them might be that woman
跟您发布的照片一模一样
from your shoot-out over there.
那他们现在在哪儿
Well, where are they now?
我们客户的实验室都安排在楼下
We keep all of our client labs downstairs,
所以我们觉得他们现在正在地下室
so we're assuming they've gone into the basement.
我刚派了几个人去查看一下
I just sent a couple of boys down to check it out.
不 别派人 把他们叫回来
No,no.No,no, withdraw your team.
封锁实验室 把他们关在下面
Lock the lab and keep them down there.
别试图抓他
Do not try to take him.
(DOOR OPENS)
你好
MARTA: Hello?
-你好 -有什么事
-GUARD: Hey, how you doing? -Can I help you?
你是一个人吗
Are you alone down here?
艾伦
Aaron?
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys.
你们不能到这儿来 你们有权限吗
You can't be down here. Do you have clearance for this level?
你们不应该来这儿的
Nobody's supposed to be down here.
我应该来这儿 我是希林医生
I'm supposed to be down here. I'm Dr. Shearing.
我们正在取样检测过程中
We're in the middle of a sampling audit.
你们这时候进来可不安全
It is not safe for you guys to be here.
我们还是上楼再谈吧
Let's straighten this out upstairs.
-别碰那个 -把东西收好 跟我们走吧
-Don't touch that. -Pack it up, let's go.
-听着 什么都不要碰 -快点 跟我走
-Look, nobody touch anything. -Come on, just follow us.
我可不想在这儿跟你吵 我会打电话给你上司
I'm not going to sit here and argue with you. I'm going to call your boss
-然后把事情弄清楚 -看着她
-and we're gonna figure it out. -Watch her.
嘿 等等
Hey, hold on a second.
(GRUNTS)
我去拿我的包 我们得走了
I'm going to get my bag. We got to go.
好
Okay.
等等 这边走
Wait. This way.
-我不知道这门通向哪儿 -你只管开门
-I don't know where this goes. -Just open it.
(DOOR BUZZES)
退后
Step back.
把工厂封锁起来 嘿 你 还有你 跟我来 快点 快
Lock it down. Hey! You! You! With me! Come on, come on, come on.
-锁上了吗 -是的 头儿
-Is that locked? -Yes, sir.
未经允许不能自由进出 明白吗
No one in, no one out. Do you understand?
你派去楼下的那三个人呢
Hey, what happened to those three guys you sent downstairs?
该死
Shit.
跟我来 你守在那儿 明白吗 给我守着
Come with me. You stay there, okay? Stay there.
自然一点
We belong here.
借过
Coming through.
(GAS HISSING)
(WORKERS SCREAMING)
(MACHINERY POWERING DOWN)
(ALARM RINGING)
你去叫上其他人 让他们去正门
MACKIE: You, go and get everyone else. Tell them to go around the front.
从东侧门出去 绕到正门
Go through the eastern doors, move around the front.
让开 都让开
MACKIE: Move! Move, people!
你听到有人回复了吗 怎么没人应答
Who have you got on this radio? Why is no one responding?
大门关上了吗
Is that gate shut?
借过 让开 快让开
Excuse me. Move, move, move!
嘿 快把大门关起来
Hey! I need that gate shut!
听着 快去正门那边 明白吗
Hey, you! Listen, go down to the main gate. Do you understand?
别让任何人进出
No one in, no one out.
嘿 你在干什么
Hey, what are you doing?
跟其他人一起去正门
Just get down to the main gate with everyone else.
(GRUNTS)
好了 退后 大家退后
All right, get back! Stay back!
给他让点地方
Give him some room.
拜托 让点地方 请给我让点地方
All right, give me some room. Give me some room, please.
他需要救治
He's going to need a doctor.
保安 保安
Security. Security!
快过来
Over here, please.
这边
Over here.
先生 能听见吗 先生
Sir, can you hear me? Sir!
他逃不远的
He can't get far.
如果他没法脱离药物 大脑会承受不住的
If he didn't viral out, he's going to run out of brain.
如果他脱离药物了 也不会有体力到处乱跑
And, if he did, then he's going to be too sick to move.
所以我们只需要尽快找到他
So, we just have to find him fast
然后杀了他 以绝后患
and kill him, once and for all.
能谈谈拉克斯的事吗
Can we talk about LARX?
拉克斯
LA RX?
拉克斯三号就在曼谷 坐飞机两小时就能赶过去
LARX-3 is in Bangkok. It's a two-hour flight.
等等 稍等片刻
Wait a minute. Just hang on, here.
我以为那计划只是个提议
I thought that was just a proposal.
让他出发
Get him out there.
泰国 曼谷
拉克斯是二代病毒项目的产物
DNA: LARX is a beta-2 stem program.
对任务的忠诚度最大化 情感最小化
Amped mission fidelity, minimized empathy.
是剔除了矛盾的踩石计划
VEN DEL: It's Treadstone without the inconsistency,
也是排除了情感因素的结果行动
Outcome without the emotional noise.
拉克斯在我们看来非常强悍
TERRY: It's looking very strong for us.
我们从未见过这样的评估
We have never seen evaluations like this.
一开始我只是以为自己不知情
This went from something I don't know about
结果发现这事已经在谋划了
to something on the drawing board,
你们现在是告诉我 这项目已经启动多时了吗
and now you're telling me it's up and running?
的确已经启动多时了 就当现在通知你了
It's up and running. Consider yourself informed.
(PANTING)
(COUGHING)
你舒服吗
DR. HILLCOTT: Are you comfortable?
是的 长官
AARON: Yes, sir.
你看上去并不舒服
You don't look comfortable.
不舒服 长官
No, sir.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
肯尼思·詹姆斯
Kenneth James.
告诉我全名 肯尼斯
Full name, Kenneth.
肯尼斯… 詹姆斯…
Kenneth... James...
基德森
AARON: Kitsom.
他们有房间
They have a room.
你还能走吗
Can you walk?
-行吗 -能走 应该能走
-Yeah? -Yeah. Yeah. I think so.
你从哪儿来 肯尼斯
DR. HILLCOTT: Where are you from, Kenneth?
什么时候
AARON: When?
在你入伍之前
Before you enlisted.
博温
Berwin.
是个小镇吗
Is that a town?
博温… 是个州立收容所
Berwin... It's a state home.
在哪个州
What state?
在里诺
In Reno.
这是测试吗
Is this a test?
没错 是测试
Yes, it is.
如果我通过 能留下来吗
If I pass, can I stay here?
你想留下来
Do you want to stay?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
很高兴听你这么说
That's good to know.
(SHUSHING)
没事了 没事了
Okay. Okay. (SHUSHING)
(AARON GROANS)
别起来 好好躺着
Okay, just lie still.
艾伦 你得… 艾伦…
Aaron, you have... Aaron...
怎么了
What?
我外套的隔层里有四万美金
There's $40,000 in the lining of my jacket.
护照都在这个包里面
In this bag, there are passports.
两本空白的 三本伪造好的 还有那家伙的手表
Two blanks and three ghosts, there's that guy's watch.
还有其他一些东西 你都拿着
There are other things, okay? You take it.
看着我
Look at me.
你逃得掉的
You can make it.
你是个战士
You're a warrior.
你能逃掉的
You can make it.
懂吗 低调一些
Okay? Stay small.
不要去机场
No airports.
装得自然一点 明白吗
Just blend in like you know, okay?
(SHUSHING)
你已经为我做得够多了
You've done enough for me.
不 我…
No, I...
你走吧
Please go.
你已经为我做得太多了
You've done enough for me.
东西都在车里
Everything's in the car.
(SIREN WAILING)
(MAN SPEAKING TAGALOG OVER RADIO)
这是测试吗
AARON: Is this a test?
没错 是测试
DR. HILLCOTT: Yes, it is.
如果我通过 能留下来吗
If I pass, can I stay here?
你想留下来
Do you want to stay?
500毫克止痛药
Paracetamol, 500 milligrams.
一天四次
Four times a day.
(SPEAKING TAGALOG)
这包免费给你
For free. This is free.
好 谢谢
Okay, good.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
(SPEAKING TAGALOG)
艾伦 快跑
Aaron, run!
(POLICE OFFICERS SHOUTING)
你在哪儿
"Where are you?"
那是信号吗
"Was that the signal?"
他们正在确认
They're asking for confirmation.
你去得太早了 不对… 我们去得太早了
"You went too soon." No... "We went too soon."
该死
Come on.
(SNIFFS)
(SPEAKING TAGALOG)
(BLOWING WHISTLES)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(SPEAKING TAGALOG)
没事的
It's okay.
(SHOUTING IN TAGALOG)
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTING)
警察 警察
Police! Police!
(SHOUTING IN TAGALOG)
蹲下
Get down!
(GUN FIRES) (GRUNTS)
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
很好 我们走
Good. Come on.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(SCREAMS)
蹲下 快蹲下
Get down, get down.
翻过去
Climb over.
快点 翻过栏杆 快翻过去
Go. Get over, get over, get over.
翻过去 抓紧栏杆
Get over. Hang on tight.
放手
Go, go!
准备好了吗 放手
You ready? Let go!
(SIREN WAILING)
好了 拿着包
Okay. Take this.
一直往前走 别回头看 快走
Just keep walking, don't look back. Go, go.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(SHOUTING)
嘿 上车
Hey, hey. Get on.
-你以前骑过摩托车吗 -没有
-You ever ridden before? -No.
戴上头盔
Take this.
警察 这边
Police, police!
抱紧我 明白吗
Hang on tight and follow me, okay?
千万别松手
Stay with me.
他手上有枪
He's got a gun!
把头低下来
Keep your head down.
他不是警察
It's not a cop.
(GASPS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
艾伦
Aaron!
(GRUNTS)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(YELLS)
(TRUCK HONKING)
(GRUNTS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
-你受伤了 -没事的
-You've been shot. -It's all right.
停车
Pull over!
快停车
Pull over.
我们得快点去港口
We just have to get to the water.
你能帮我查一下吗
DITA: Can you check that for me?
那还需要多久
VENDEL: How long is that going to take?
快点
Come on.
我一会儿再打过去
DITA: We'll get back to you.
有消息了吗
Anything?
没有
-No. -(SIGHS)
警察没追上他
VENDEL: The cops are out.
他们也没线索了
They lost the trail.
艾伦
Aaron!
艾伦 醒醒 快醒醒 艾伦
Aaron! Aaron! Aaron! Aaron!
(GROANS)
你没事吧
Are you okay?
-没事吧 -没事
-Yeah? -Yeah.
你能帮帮我们吗
Can you help us?
求你了
Please.
应该马上就到了
Should be up there now.
他说这就是他们过夜的房间
He said it's the room where they spent the night.
六年前我们就遇到过踩石计划造成的麻烦
PAULSEN: Well, we had a problem with Treadstone six years ago.
黑石楠计划的
The Blackbriar program,
所有细节都在各位手边的行动报告里
detailed in the operations report you have before you,
此计划是有人私自启用
was activated solely to capture
用来抓捕踩石计划里叛逃的一名特工
a Treadstone operative gone rogue.
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
帕梅拉 你会如何应对
WOMAN: Pam, what are you going to do?
暂时无可奉告
We have nothing for you now.
我不知道帕梅拉·兰迪
I don't know Pamela Landy's reasons
不惜犯罪 帮助美国敌人的原因
for criminally assisting an enemy of the United States.
但事实是 她没有任务权限
But the fact is, she lacked the operational clearance
更没其它途径能接触到各位手边
to access, much less interpret, the information you have
机密报告里的文件
in the classified file before you.
帕梅拉 有传言称你将被起诉 是真的吗
MAN: Pam, there's a rumor that you're going to be indicted, is it true?
-麦克 评论几句吧 -你被传讯了吗
-Mike, can you comment? -WOMAN: Have you been subpoenaed?
我们是自愿来这里参加会议的
ATTORNEY: We're here voluntarily. We came for a meeting.
你和杰森·伯恩联系过吗
WOMAN: Have you had any contact with Jason Bourne?
你是否收到过目标名单
MAN: Did you receive a target letter or not?
我们明天还会见到你吗
Are we going to see you tomorrow?
我只想感谢上帝 有人能在
VOSEN: I just thank God that there were hands steady enough
她泄露给媒体的这些文件
to make sure that the documents she tried to shop to the press
造成进一步危害前
were contained before they could
把文件回收了
do any more harm than they already have.
你是否还会出席特工委员会的会议
WOMAN: Are you still scheduled to appear at the House Intelligence Committee?
当然 听着 如果还有进一步问题 请联系我的律师 好吗
Yes, I am. Look, anything else is going to have to come from my attorneys, okay?
你后悔做出此前的声明吗
MAN: Do you regret your earlier statement?
我后悔过很多事情 但这件事情绝不后悔
I regret a lot of things. I'm not sure that one is on the list.
谢谢各位
Thank you, guys.
(SPEAKS TAGALOG)
嘿
Hey.
我们迷路了吗
Are we lost?
没有
No.
只是在想能去哪些地方
Just looking at our options.
我倒希望我们真的迷路了
I was kind of hoping we were lost.